Thank you.
These people, Lord, don't hear me, but hear you through me that, just like a bumper video, so that we are poured out for you, Lord.
Like I said, bless this message, bless this people and opinions, as you preach this name and pray, and we do all this for the neighbor's food and the glory of God in Jesus Christ. Amen.
All right, so today, I'm going to give my name to you.
So those of you that don't know me, my name is Corey Smith, and I have the privilege of serving on the governance for here at Kansas Community.
But I'll also give the distinct privilege of bringing you the message today.
As you're joining us this morning, we've just finished up our Resurrecting Rumor Series that we've been in since about the Easter season.
But let's be honest, we never really stop preaching to Jesus Christ's Resurrecting.
But we're kind of in this in-between series.
Like Ryan said, he stole some of my thunder there with the announcements.
The Dr. Moon lectures come up in a couple weeks, and who's reason made plans to join us for that?
But we're prepping for the season of Target Church Membership.
Matt's coming back to join us.
He's out in Yellowstone now, but he's going to come back to Yellowstone and join us for that.
So Ryan kind of gave me three ways to just preach whatever the Spirit kind of laid on my heart.
So today, we're going to talk about something that's, I don't know that it's not necessarily funny,
but, I mean, I feel like I say that every time, but, okay.
But I think that the sermons are necessary in our church environments.
I think we talked about Saul, who, in his evolution of zealous Judaism to Christianity,
was renamed Paul, or the Apostle Paul.
And the framework for that sermon was around the idea of certainty planning.
That we miss who Jesus is, and what his mission is, and our pursuit of always being right.
And hopefully that hits you guys, too.
I was up here sobbing.
Because, like, how many times have we been guilty about it?
And from some of the posts I saw on social media, I think that hits you guys as well.
So that wasn't, in my mind, a fun sermon, but it was something we needed in our church community.
The heart of this message, I think, ties to the heart of that message.
Church, we can either help us or in the kingdom of God more fully in this world,
or I think we can be the biggest stumbling block for the world to see Jesus.
Okay.
Let me read that.
Church, we can either help us in the kingdom of God more fully for this world,
or we can be the biggest stumbling block for the world to see Jesus.
So I think some things have been lost over the ages.
And I think we're feeling some of the repercussions of that within our current church area,
especially in the Western church.
I had a conversation with a friend of mine this week,
and I told them that I think the hardest conversations are often the most destructive.
This is a hard conversation because, I'll be honest with you, I struggle with this.
And I think a lot of us struggle with this.
So it's going to be personal.
It's probably going to matter.
Heads up.
But Church, I want us to do better.
I want to do better.
I want you to do better.
Not because we are better,
but because I believe we serve a better team than this world has to offer.
The ideas we're going to be wrestling with today are around the spheres of confession and repentance.
But primarily, we're going to hinge on the why of those things,
because I think the why,
one of the things that's so difficult for us to get over,
why we don't care for those things.
I think some of you even probably changed a little bit
when I said something about confession and repentance today.
But I think the why forces us to dig into the deepest parts of our hearts.
Confession and repentance will be secondary to the primary conversation today.
I think that's weird for Church language,
to make confession and repentance secondary,
but speak with me.
Last week, we talked about, again,
Saul asking the question of the resurrected Jesus,
who are you and what do you want me to do?
That's why we're here.
We want to know more about this God incarnate in flesh, Jesus,
and we want to know what to do next.
Because I think God's more to the character of God in Christ,
and it also gives us some reflections on what we are and what we're to do.
And my brain, hopefully, this is going to tell us only those two questions.
I want to tell you a little story about myself today.
I'm not excited about it.
I told my mom, like, she's totally not excited about that, but not either.
But, one, I got three reasons, like, I'm a good speaker, got three reasons.
I'm not a fan of guys that get up here and just talk about themselves.
Like, I'm putting that out there.
I'm not guilty of them today, because, like, I'm a hypocrite.
But, and just two, hopefully it's not three or, like, oh, man, or it's awesome.
It's hopefully one you can identify with and hope you resonate with those teaching you're doing.
And three, because I desire every one of my messages to be used in the Holy Spirit,
to envelop you and grade you and use your personal mission for your life.
And I love being able to serve you in this way, by people and teachings.
I also want you to walk away realizing that I'm a broken person,
only striving to claim to Jesus' righteousness.
Because there is no goodness in me, a personal God.
And I think that's where we have a misconception.
That's free for any of us up here on stage.
Any person who steps foot on the stage, we have all family come free to the glory of God.
Every single person on this stage is in need of a Savior,
and we have an intercessor to stand for us and advocate for us before a holy God.
See, we have found that in Jesus, a personal Jesus, on the midst.
And so is everyone else up here on the stage.
I was having a conversation last weekend in this idea that we as Christians are sheep, right?
But I think, so often, we don't correlate that with the teachers.
We're sheep as well.
We're just called to a different yesterday.
We're about it.
I'm in just as much need of a Savior as everybody else is.
Yeah, I made my procession of faith that Jesus is at a very young age,
my uncle's person, basically, West Virginia during vacation Bible school.
Did all the right things.
I raised my hand when no one was looking.
And I told you, I was playing.
Like, it was, it was the perfect formula.
My grandfather actually took me backstage in the back room
and asked me some clarifying questions to make sure I knew what I was doing.
I was baptized a couple weeks later in my home church by a pastor.
I love the way you're for a Jesus Christ.
But when I was a teenager, when I was in my early 20s,
I wasn't the guy up here on stage having a passion and desire to see people sign in and grow in Jesus.
I was someone who was wild, rebellious.
I was just looking to have a good time.
I rebelled against that idea of just trying to burn a moral checklist
was something I was supposed to do because that's a good Christian spirit.
My parents enrolled me in a Christian school that I attended my whole life.
We went to church there.
I went to school there.
It was almost an every facet of my life.
And in the 10th grade, I always keep going out of school because of my accident and my rebellion.
I wanted nothing to do with church.
Because all I saw there were self-righteous efforts.
I wanted nothing to do with the church for a long time.
During those years, people had formed a reputation of me, and I had formed a reputation of them.
Me as a best-looking Christian who wasn't willing to submit an experience with a group of self-righteous
getting teachers who were isolated from the people of Jesus who called them to disciples.
It wasn't until Samantha and I approached back years later to do our wedding that I found my way back in the church,
reforming some of the ideas that I had placed upon them.
It's on the stage for y'all.
Jack had retired from the church I was expelled from a couple of years before I was kicked out,
and had actually planted a new church several years after his retirement.
What was the speculation of him doing the wedding was that we would attend this new church for six months
before he would go to the church before he would go to the wedding.
And I said simply, I agree.
But in the next six months I've had, I've found people that either knew my reputation and didn't care,
or that knew nothing of me and I could form a new reputation.
But certainly, I found a community that was willing to succeed, but they didn't have it all together.
But they were brought in too.
And that's really all the spirit needed to study.
Genuine people willing to be authentic with each other, willing to be vulnerable,
willing to talk through difficult topics together.
Some of us have lost to tell you this, but like, too often,
it's preservation of our own reputations that makes us self-righteous,
and it makes us being hypocritical because we're unwilling to sell our weaknesses.
But I think too often that's what we're trying to say.
We're trying to have to cherish this reputation that we have worked so hard for.
So, it's just for your unconsciously, we want to protect our reputation.
And like I said, if I didn't struggle with it,
and if I didn't see it as an epidemic in the church, I wouldn't be talking about it.
There's a cloud out there, so I don't know if y'all are dealing with it,
or if I didn't call it an hour, I'll go to it.
But the most constructive conversations, I believe, are often and let's just call.
So, we're going to talk today about reputation
and how it feels to affect our Christian life
and some of the pitfalls and feelings around protecting it
instead of being obedient to God.
And some of the people from my past are still amazed
that a person like me is up here preaching a sermon.
You know, that's right.
Anyway, there's a funny story.
So, one time, somebody had been on the road at a birthday party
and someone who was a spouse member of the field of school
and they were like teenagers and friends,
we had the fellow who was like,
oh, we had a couple of weddings there in these unirals
and maybe even one of them, like three.
And some of my thoughts was, like, it's so amazing that we've got to use this people like that.
And, like, real people, real loud, it's the way I can go, like, hear the Jerry Sprayers go, like, real quick.
You did not want me to say it on the boat.
But that's what I want.
But in my weakness, Christ is glorified.
And in my repentance, King of Jesus is exalted.
That's the heart of this message.
The spirit really laid on me and it was in my heart a couple weeks ago
when I prepared the first one for a monthly board meeting.
And you're coming to your framework around Christian leadership,
but it's not just Christian leadership.
It's, I think, fundamental to these disciples of Jesus.
I was curious in Facebook when I came across this place.
Do we have something you hope that I would slide up?
Oh, it's not going to.
It is.
Nobody said what I would say to this person is for hope that I would search.
It's not the reputation of our pastors, our church, or our services that we should be building.
It is the reputation of Jesus.
And I was like, man, this is so good.
It seems like it's the perfect environment to talk about that.
It seems like it's the perfect environment to talk about reputation.
It's the good, the bad, and the pitfalls.
It's not the reputation of our pastors.
A guy like Ryan a lot.
He's very speaker.
He's super awesome and hip.
It's not that.
He's dressed as well.
It's not the reputation of our church.
Well, it's everyone's super friendly and not super churchy.
It's not the reputation of our services.
We're in and out an hour.
He never goes over.
Kids starts, down thousands.
Wow.
Right?
See, those are a lot of things that I'm guilty of saying those things.
But in years, however, how does that come back to the reputation of Jesus that we're supposed to care about?
Folks, this is, how, the question is, how is Jesus' reputation being viewed for years?
Ryan this morning read, try this in 1st, 20, 20, 20, 20, 20, 20, 20.
And what I want to do today is, for us in the church, as a priesthood of believers,
is to know and understand the responsibilities and the pitfalls of reputation.
More specifically, thriving towards and systematically building or maintaining a reputation.
How much do we feel to him?
I'm going to say that again.
It doesn't get free.
It doesn't fly, but that's what I said.
But we will strive for and we'll potentially spend for systematically building or maintaining a reputation.
The word translated as blameless in Titus 1, 6 is a negligence.
I think it's going to be something like in a couple weeks, so don't tell them I'm sorry, right?
The next one's going to get real bad, right?
The word for above reproach in 1st Timothy 3, 2 is an epiletope.
Put that one back at me.
These two Greek words carry a meaning of that which nothing can take hold upon.
The Bible commentator Adam Clark uses the illustration of a boxing.
Really boxing fans in the house?
Jason's always behind me.
Just one.
But just like a spiritual bastard who sends every part of his body and gives their parents no place but here.
So a blameless person or a person with a blameless reputation gives the outside world no extreme place to attack that character.
And I would argue that the world will even still, with a truly blameless reputation, still attack the reputation.
So the question is, who benefits from a blameless reputation?
Does Jesus benefit from our blameless reputation?
Do we give him glory for any good that might come out of us?
Or do we benefit from it?
How people see and engage with us largely depends on our reputation.
So brothers and sisters, the goal here is not to dwell on about a bad reputation or how to maintain a good one.
Where I can give you five checklists and do these things when you're a good Christian.
But instead, the question is, how do we as a body fertilize a Christ-like reputation?
So the warning is that we could focus on building a reputation or maintaining one for our own personal beginnings.
Which leads to a road to destruction.
Or, we could up Philippians 2, 5-3-7.
This poem, read this.
So we're going to focus in on this idea of Jesus having no reputation.
But I wanted to take a few moments to expose this verse so that we're all on the same page.
I want to spend some time here because I want to stay coherent in the message.
But I think it's something definitely worth mentioning.
Ron's got those cool things.
You guys haven't followed it on Instagram.
What's it called?
Cutting Room 4?
Yeah, Cutting Room 4.
Where he kind of takes some of that.
He does a lot of work to tell the message and some of that extra stuff.
You're like, you know, this is good, but we don't exist.
So check that out.
But Jesus, who being in the form of God, did not consider it robbery to be equal with God.
Or as other translations put it, did not consider equality with God something to be used to his own advantage.
See, Jesus, we believe, is God.
So this is important because not only did God make the world, but when we broke it, he put in the place of corrections for it.
A redemption for falling for us in himself.
See, God created the world for humans and God to fellowship together.
And through that rebellion, we severed that connection.
But God putting the payment of the rebellion on the shoulders of Jesus onto the shoulders of himself in flesh because we could never fully satisfy the justice of God in our age.
God passed the judgment, but God also paid the penalty.
See, what Jesus didn't do was cling to that advantage.
The God of the universe, imagine this, the God of the universe that created us and everything in it,
allowed us to murder him on a Roman torture device.
So that he could bring us back in the fellowship with himself.
See, that's the God of love that he would justify mankind through our sinful murder of his son.
I want you to start with that.
And if anyone could use their reputation as my opinions and as Jesus, right, it was bad.
But instead, he made himself of no reputation, taking on the form of a servant, a human.
Isaiah 53 tells us that the Messiah would have no beauty or majesty to attract us to him.
Nothing in his appearance would make us desire him.
That he would be despised and rejected by mankind.
So my goal here today is to host a conversation about reputation and potentially no reputation
and how it intimately ties into how the world sees us and sees our king through our actions and words.
So we as Christians are quick to call out heresy when it comes to words or doctrine.
But why are we not so quick to call out heresy when it comes to the word of the enemy?
So I want to address something that I do as an epidemic in the church.
And I'm using, when I say the church, I know the Christians using, I'm talking to you guys and everybody else,
but the capital speed church, the world church, the global church.
Unless your attention has been drawn elsewhere, you've probably seen some of the scandalous documentaries
and series making their way around about church figures.
Are we familiar with this part?
Y'all have been, I know well, in the church, let's say.
There's been plenty of tales like the Rouse and Saul of Mars Hill.
That's a matter.
He'll start with those, just to name a few.
So there's a term out there that I want to make you all familiar with.
It's a little bit spicy, so I'm going to give you the warning beforehand, but it's called failure porn.
Are we familiar with this time that we heard?
No?
Okay.
Because failure porn is used as a way to describe out-of-assimation with something terrible.
Like not being able to look away from a train wreck or the bottle methods of the interstate
that they just want to slow down for the sake of curiosity.
See, failure porn is often attributed to these types of church media because we excuse them as such.
Church, I don't want us to excuse these critiques away.
Although there's a failure porn, people love watching the church video.
It might be true, but what I want is I want us to learn and grade from them.
Because the world is watching how we, the Calvinist in church, react.
So our neighbors are watching how the world reacts.
So when it's wrong, it's important to acknowledge that we're wrong.
And one of the worst things that happens in a building for someone to admit fault.
See, to admit the support for confession as a week, that's what that means, like, they can not be.
That's someone's opinion one that it takes more courage and strength to do that than to have something.
See, if you can't, and most of them unwilling, let's be frank, to explain your faults through conversation with trusted people and hear their lovingly critique for you
and why you made these videos, they're going to lose your, they're going to lose your, they're going to lose space in your ability to spreading strength for you in the future.
Especially when that thing you've been hiding is right to like.
See, something that's confessed and repented as can't be used to accuse you any longer.
It can be used to bring justice and accountability, but it can, you can not be accused of something you've admitted.
But why then do we hold on?
Or, why do you hold on?
Because I value my reputation.
But I'm trying to learn that too.
You know, I think we need to hold on to Jesus, not our main reputations.
And as reflections on Christian leadership, kind of now when I'm first to this, it's rejecting the temptation to be relevant.
Ooh, that's all I love.
Can we put that up?
Oh, there's any doubt.
I am deeply convinced that the Christian leader of the future is called to be completely irrelevant.
And to stand in this world with nothing to offer but his or her own vulnerable self.
That is the way Jesus came to us to reveal God's love.
See, this is not just the fundamental position of church leadership.
I think this is the fundamental position of a disciple of Jesus Christ.
I'm going to leave you with some of those burdens.
Leave the next slide down.
We are not called to be caretakers of our own reputation.
We're called to be our medium disciples of Jesus Christ.
See, if we obediently love our neighbors, speak truth in love, love mercy, walk humbly with our God,
and our reputations are maintaining the ones we want, it could be of little consequence to us.
We're going to put a best slide of hope that we did, though.
I love my church.
I want our church to succeed and grow.
Maybe in depth if we're with, but I want this thing to be a success.
Part of the conversations we've had in the church murder, part of the resonation I have with it is,
I want a generational church.
I want something that I can hand down to my children so that they can take up the mantle of Christ's work here in my sister.
See, Ryan and Michelle have done an amazing job at this school about collaborating.
So they meet up with local pastors once a month to eat and pray together.
So, Hope Valley is one of those churches.
Kansas Community is one of those churches.
So, I've got to know Sam's through that, and Sam Rogers is one of the pastors at Hope Valley.
And I messaged him, because I want to give political page to him.
And I was like, hey, man, think about preaching a sermon on this.
Can I use this slide?
And he was like, yeah, yeah, it is for sure.
Not only was he cool with me using this, he was cool with me not giving Hope Valley credit for me.
He also offered me his sermon notes on it, because he was like, man, I've already done the work.
Here it is.
And I was like, if you don't know this, that's big in the church world.
See, people of no reputation that care about Jesus being a friend over themselves, that's what that is.
So, we all want our churches to succeed.
We all want our friends to come to our cool churches.
Do what I want more than that.
But I honestly would rather see the kingdom of God and what I say to you, as it is in heaven.
Don't want to see lives transformed.
I want to see poverty eradicated.
I want to see the gospel of Jesus spread to Jerusalem, to Gios, to Mariel, to the other most parts of the world.
See, it concerns me not if quarry plays a role in that.
What concerns me is how do people experience the reputation of Jesus being made?
I always tell you a funny story.
I was talking down the road the other day and I had a million faith forms in my mind.
And once I collected my thoughts, there was this obnoxious sound of nonsense, of nonsense.
It was a seatbelt thing that went off.
And I forgot what my seatbelt was.
It was a lot of people.
A lot of people.
But, all of a sudden, it's been said that I didn't need to pay attention to the most annoying sound of the planet.
The seatbelt thing.
If anybody remember, I wanted to do a story, like, get on, or a short video of it.
But if anybody remember, it's done and done with it, where Lloyd does to get on the middle seat if he wants to hear the most annoying sound of the planet.
Like, you know, like, to me is the seatbelt thing that won't come off.
It's just been, like, super anxiety.
Like, it makes me a worse driver, too.
But, there's all these things.
Like, people that are in the excellence for the seatbelts, they've been from serious injuries.
They're like, it's probably a seatbelt like something.
I'll wear mine when I'm not even in the car.
You're like, okay, that's cool.
And that, like, 12-3 prison seatbelt safety.
I haven't talked about that time, seatbelt safety.
So, you're like, yeah, man, I'm turning.
And you never stop talking about the bag on the seatbelt.
Like, okay, you pound them in the house.
I'm putting it on.
Like, please stop telling me about it.
And whatever you do, just make the video go away.
Every time you get in the car, they're like, right, put that on.
And you're like, I'm in the car, so I'm putting it on.
Give me a break.
Do you know who preaches seatbelt safety is a lot of us?
People that recognize that the seatbelt saved their lives.
Do you know who preaches Jesus the most authentically and vulnerable?
People that recognize that they'd be dead and lost in the same person.
So, if I don't want us to be seatbelt Christians,
I don't want to be a seatbelt Christian.
The ones that not only talk about Jesus all the time,
but the ones that try to act like him, too.
There's a reference from Black to Marries and some podcasts about the church earlier.
It's kind of that epidemic I saw.
And the epidemic I'm referring to is reputation.
So, it gives those sins a meaning of my time and attention
because I want to learn some of the mistakes.
So that through the work of the Spirit,
they're not on my own,
but through the work of the Spirit,
I can do my dead-level best to avoid them.
So you're overarching things for me from my perspective
as I fear about these mega-pensers falling from the start of this earth.
But they're caring too much about their own reputation,
either building it or protecting it,
to confess those sins and have no reputation for the person Jesus.
Can you put up Philippians 2 again?
You know what?
I'm going to go off the test.
Can we read this together?
All right, I'll start.
Let this mind be in you, which was also in Christ Jesus.
He, being in the form of God,
did not considerate robbery to be equal with God,
but made himself of no reputation,
taking on the form of a bombed servant
and coming in the likeness of man.
Now, not usually,
confessing,
not usually much on the New King James,
but that really drove it home for me.
Now, don't you say that Jesus made himself of a bad reputation
or a questionable reputation,
like let's put those thoughts out of our minds.
Do you need to say that he made himself of a good reputation,
but simply no reputation?
See, that is that reputation's image,
prestige, power, prominence,
and other typos of leadership
were not only devalued by Jesus,
but that they were purposely dismissed.
So this is the challenge for us.
So we have come to believe
that the development of a good reputation
is part and parcel of living a holy and ethical life.
But in that assumption lies an insidious temptation.
See, reputation and pride are so closely linked
that oftentimes it's difficult for us to consider one without the other.
See, when we're concerned about our reputation,
we cannot help but be attentive to what people think of us.
Spence it is to criticize them.
And always in order to protect a wrong notion
or unfair judgment of our work and character.
See, this leads us to hide sin in our lives.
To be desperate to protect something that we see as valuable
and not be our own irrelevant, vulnerable selves.
See, this is my lesson in one in church.
Find people whom you love and trust
and who love and trust isn't to keep you accountable.
I don't trust myself in a vacuum.
But God doesn't want to say this.
But God told me to go with us.
That is.
Thanks, baby.
And if you're convinced you're right
and everybody else around you is telling you you're right,
say this is all you're right.
Don't put myself in a vacuum and neither is to you.
God wants us to have community
and not just some love and a from us.
Ooh, that's rough.
He also wants community to correct us when we're right.
Justin Miller asked this question in one of our town halls
and he said it was specifically.
I told him how you're going to describe that today.
I think he doesn't mind,
but I don't even know how to buy it,
so it was completely due to him, too.
But he asked a good question.
With membership,
I was in one of our town hall,
so with membership,
who are we subject to?
Who holds us accountable?
Are we submitting to him or them?
What's that look like?
That's something that sucks with me
because that's the beauty of campus community.
In a couple weeks when we do charter membership,
we're not asking you to submit the rounds.
We're not asking you to submit to the governance board
or people denominations.
We're asking that you submit to the community
that we are each accountable to each other.
See, oftentimes it's not just a question that's raised.
What purpose do I get?
Right?
You go to the gospel.
You want purpose.
But was this not a specific question
that would be more applicable would be,
if you don't love these people,
what do you do?
That's the heart of the Christian community.
It's not, what do I get,
but what do I do,
especially for these people
that I want to do community with.
How can lives be impacted not just by me,
but by Jesus who we need?
Reputation and pride are so closely linked
that I, again, think it's difficult for us
to consider one without the other.
Church, may we be speak about Christians
that say badly we're humans,
but are not only willing to talk about humans,
but are willing to lay aside our pride and reputation
if I don't have any workplaces.
So what does that mean for you?
What's the principle application?
I've already listened to a couple of groups,
so hopefully you find yourself with one of them.
If you consider yourself a follower of Jesus,
someone can submit to his worship over your life.
The practical exercise is this.
And like any good speaker,
I'll break it in the name of three easy,
made-taking points.
What is the areas in your life
that you're holding on to in fear,
and if it comes to light,
your reputation could be written?
Remember, you can't be accused
of something that's inconsistent.
In Galatians 5,
where the Apostle Paul talks about
the freedom in Christ who has set us free,
and not to be burdened again by slavery.
So I'd ask you,
are you truly free in Christ?
Or do you have some kid and student
that's keeping you in slavery?
I'd like to do this myself.
I'd like to form a philosophical argument
to help me understand things.
Most of the time,
I want people to poke holes
in my own argument
and make me more concrete.
So who knows is my argument?
I'm telling you,
the wrestle that I don't have
on the Apostle Paul's
almost on a different basis.
Short-term,
confession's going to stop.
The long-term,
losers, freedom.
You're no more hiding your sins
or your cause.
You can take off the mask
and lift the wall of faith
but you've got it all together.
Being freely free in Christ.
Short-term as having something
might seem like some false sense of security
but that yoke and burden
will grow heavier and heavier
and it's as long as it's hidden
because you'll always fear
it coming to light
when we're in that reputation
you've built.
Two,
can people see the reputation
of Jesus
through your willingness
to be vulnerable,
authentic,
and sister loving?
Not just you.
That's the easy part.
When you're at work,
school,
and you go out to eat,
when you interact
with the outside world,
are you spreading
the gospel of Jesus Christ
not just with words
but with actions?
And three,
I want you guys to do this.
I talked to,
I just came up
in a silence I'm taking
recently
but I want you to check
your moral compass.
Do you live a,
do you want to live a pious life
because that's what
good Christians do?
Do you want to have,
or because you want to have
a reputation,
don't you?
Do you want to,
do you strive to live
a pious life
because life,
that's eat not Christian,
you understand that
without Jesus,
you would have no hope.
You'd be dead
in the last few years
for Jesus.
You know,
don't think about
where that comes from,
not self-righteous.
Remember,
we can either
further the kingdom
of God in this world
or we can be the biggest
stumbling back to it.
How's that,
do you think,
Christian?
I'm sorry,
you're listening.
Alright,
you're going to choose.
so,
if you are here today
and you can,
you don't consider yourself
as hard as you do,
we're glad you're here.
I'm glad you're here.
I'm sorry for some
of the negative experiences
that you've had
around church
and church people.
But I'm thankful
for you being here today.
I'll be the first
to admit,
we don't always do
those things
that Jesus called us to.
I can't speak
to what someone else
is from,
but Lord knows,
I've made myself
serious face.
I think he's called
you for some reason.
I encourage you
to give this
such thing a try,
even if it's not scared.
I use this phrase a lot,
but I really like it,
but I don't think
that some of this community
has a monopoly
on the gospel
and we trust it.
We truly just want
to connect with Jesus
trusting
and please
bring his former
power in the resurrection
and lordship
over your life,
which brings salvation.
And finding a community
that has faith
to be intimately
and well on us.
I'm not even upset
if you give it to the money,
but for me,
I needed it.
I needed it six months.
And that was
six months
before our wedding.
Next month,
minutes to minutes,
I'll celebrate
11 years maybe.
The church has been
an important part
of our lives.
So my hope
and prayer
is that
you find a community
of authentic people
who genuinely
love Jesus
and have tried
no best to find them.
I'll leave you
with this today
before having
Ryan
come up to
the least
in communion
that we believe
salvation
is both
an event
and a process
and if the Holy Spirit
is leading you
to either start
the day
this life
of dedication
and service
to him
or to lay
something aside
that you've had
to lay it
at the feet
of the cross,
I'm trying to
find somebody
to come to you.
I'll be
available
Ryan
and many
other
services.
But at the end
of the day
start here.
Thank you guys.